（1938年6月）
在1930年的这十年中 即使是像梅乔克力斯这般的大城
"In the decade of the 1930s even the great city of Metropolis...
也无法抵挡全世界衰退的冲击
"...was not spared the ravages of the worldwide depression.
那时代充满了恐惧与迷惑
"In the times of fear and confusion...
通知大众的工作
"...the job of informing the public was the responsibility...
成为星球日报的责任
"...of the Daily Planet.
那伟大的公众的报纸
"A great metropolitan newspaper...
它以清晰事理与真实为名
"...whose reputation for clarity and truth had become a symbol of hope...
成为梅乔克力斯市希望的象征
"...for the city of Metropolis."
主演：马龙.白兰度
主演：真.克曼
片名：超人
这不是幻想
This is no fantasy.
不是不小心的产品的狂野想像
No careless product of wild imagination.
不 我的好友们
No, my good friends...
我今天...
...these indictments...
带到这里的这些控诉
...I've brought you today...
是在这听证会上控告某些个人
...specific charges listed herein against the individuals...
他们的超感能力限制我们的选择
...their acts of treason. Their ultimate aim of sedition.
这些是…
These...
无法否认的事实
...are matters of undeniable fact.
我现在请求你们宣布你们的判决
I ask you now to pronounce judgment...
对那些指控而言
...on those accused.
对这一个…
On this...
这个没有大脑只会动手的
...this mindless aberration...
他唯一的表达是破坏与暴力
...whose only means of expression are wanton violence and destruction.
对这女人尔莎
On the woman, Ursa...
她对全人类毫无理由的憎恨
...whose perversions and unreasoning hatred of all mankind...
甚至已经威胁克莱顿星的孩童们
...have threatened even the children of the Planet Krypton.
终于 萨得将军
Finally, General Zod.
一度被这个议会信任
Once trusted by this Council...
萨得本身负责 星球水晶的防护维持
...charged with maintaining the defense of the Planet Krypton itself.
企图攻击而发动革命 同时对这神圣的普拉顿市想染指
Chief Architect of this intended revolution and author of this insidious plot...
想要建立一种新秩序的胡说八道
...to establish a new order amongst us...
以他自己成为绝对的统治者
...with himself as absolute ruler.
你们都听到了证物
You have heard the evidence.
现在我们要听议会的决定
The decision of the Council will now be heard.
有罪
Guilty!
有罪…有罪
有罪
Guilty!
投票一定是你所预先控制的
The vote must be unanimous, Jor-El.
因此 现在变成了你的决定
It has therefore now become your decision.
若是你希望 只有你一个人 要惩戒我们
You alone will condemn us if you wish...
而你一个人我要对你付全权之责
...and you alone will be held responsible by me!
加入我们
Join us!
你以前也以反对议会决定而闻名
You have been known to disagree with the Council before.
你有机会成为新秩序中的要角 仅次于我的第二把交椅
Yours could become an important voice in the new order, second only to my own!
我提供你一个绝佳的机会
I offer you a chance for greatness, Jor-El!
接受吧 加入我们吧
Take it! Join us!
你会跪在我的面前的 乔罗
You will bow down before me, Jor-El.
我发誓 不论要花什么代价
I swear it! No matter that it takes an eternity!
你会跪在我的面前的
You will bow down before me!
不只是你
Both you and then one day...
还有你的子孙
...your heirs!
原谅我 …原谅我
Forgive me, forgive me...
你们不能忽视这个事实
You can not ignore this fact.
这是自杀
It's suicide.
不 更糟 是祸延子孙
No, it's worse, it's genocide.
觉悟吧 乔罗
Be warned, Jor-El.
议会已经消灭了你的陆地理论
The Council has already evaluated this outlandish theory of yours.
朋友们 你们都晓得我既不急也不强求
My friends, you know me to be neither rash nor impulsive.
我不会给予广泛及支持的声明
I am not given to wild unsupported statements...
而我告诉你们 我们必需立刻疏散这颗星球
...and I tell you that we must evacuate this planet immediately.
问题不是出在你所提出的疑问
I don't question your data.
事实是无法否认的
The facts are undeniable.
是你的结论找不到支持的论点
It's your conclusions we find unsupportable.
这颗星球在30天之内会爆炸
This planet will explode within 30 days.
若是不会更快的话
If not sooner.
我告诉你 克莱顿星只是单纯的地壳震动
I tell you Krypton is simply shifting its orbit.
乔罗
Jor-El...
讲点道理
...be reasonable.
我的朋友
My friend...
我从来没有是其他的样子 这一场疯狂是你的
...I have never been otherwise. This madness is yours.
讨论终结
This discussion is terminated.
议会的决定是最后的决定
The decision of the Council is final.
任何由你所创造的企图
Any attempt by you to create...
在大众面前 想利用天候去影响到这星球
...a climate of fear and panic among the populace...
必需在我们的督导之下 而且依照所交代的方向去做
...must be deemed by us an act of insurrection.
你指责我不听令行事?
You would accuse me of insurrection?
现在对生命慈悲变成罪行了吗?
Has it now become a crime to cherish life?
你会听从议会的决定吗?
Will you abide by the Council's decision?
我会保持沉默
I will remain silent.
不论我 或是我的内人
Neither I, nor my wife...
会离开这里
...will leave Krypton.
你做完了吗?
Have you finished?
几乎好了
Nearly.
这是唯一的出路
It's the only answer, Lara.
若是你和我们一起留在这里
If he remains here with us...
你会死 就像我们会死一般
...he will die as surely as we will.
但为何选地球?乔罗
But why Earth, Jor-El?
他们的科技落后我们几千年
They're primitives, thousands of years behind us.
他需要那个优点去活下来
He will need that advantage to survive.
他们非常的正常
Their atmosphere will...
那是他停留之地
...sustain him.
你会弄清楚他们的强夺性
He will defy their gravity.
他会长的像他们的一份子
He will look like one of them.
他不会是他们的一份子
He won't be one of them.
不
No.
他留在水晶结构中会使他强壮
His dense molecular structure will make him strong.
他会非常优秀与众不同
He'll be odd. Different.
他会非常的快 终极上会非常的荣耀
He'll be fast. Virtually invulnerable.
被孤立 一个人
Isolated. Alone.
他不会是一个人
He will not be alone.
永远不会是一个人
He will never be alone.
他会旅行很远 我的小葛洛
You will travel far, my little Kal-El.
我们永远不会离开你
But we will never leave you.
即使在我们面对死亡之时
Even in the face of our death...
我们生命中丰富的一面
...the richness of our lives...
会是你的
...shall be yours.
我所拥有的 我所学到的 一切我所感觉的
All that I have, all that I've learned, everything I feel...
所有我所拥有的
...all this and more, I...
我会灌注到你自身上 儿子
...I bequeath you, my son.
你会在内心中负荷着我
You will carry me inside you...
在你的一生中
...all the days of your life.
你会把我的力量变成你自己的
You will make my strength your own...
由你的眼中看到我的一生
...see my life through your eyes...
而你的生命也会在我眼中出现
...as your life will be seen through mine.
儿子会变成父亲的父亲
The son becomes the father, and the father...
儿子
...the son.
这是所有我所能…
This is all I...
我所能给予你的 葛洛
...all I can send you, Kal-El.
这是爱因斯坦所谓的相对论
... which Einstein called his theory of relativity.
全都藏在你面前的水晶中
...in the crystals before you...
这是由几千颗星球上所得到的...
... is the total accumulation of all literature and scientific fact from dozens...
科学事实的累积
... of other worlds...
它们全分布在第28银河系
... spanning the 28 known galaxies.
在你到达的早期 所有克莱顿星复杂的关系…
Early Chinese writings point out the complex relationship...
所有的决定都是过去几千年…
By carrying this complex equation to its ultimate power, my son...
在过去的这些成就
Chief among these powers will be your sight...
会成为你的视觉 力量 听觉
... your strength, your hearing...
你能为自己准备的能力 几乎是没有限度的速度
... your ability to propel yourself at almost limitless speed.
关于我们星球的早期历史 及早期对蒙赛克人的星球血战
The early history of our universe was a bloody mosaic of interplanetary war.
及你会经过的六个银行系
Each of the six galaxies which you will pass through...
都拥有他们各自的法律
... contain their own individual law of space and time.
在太空中所不允许的 是干扰人类的历史
It is forbidden for you to interfere with human history.
- 什么? - 那是什么?
- What! - What was that?
不会全凑到一块了吗? 你能不能…
Now wouldn't that beat all get out. Well, you...
哦 天
Oh, Pa!
哦 上帝
Oh, my.
这么多快乐的年头
All these years, as happy as we've been...
我一直向上帝祈祷 给我们一个孩子
...how I've prayed the good Lord would see fit to give us a child.
亲爱的 请把那抹布递给我
Honey, will you hand me that rag up there.
你最好慢慢来 强纳森
You take things easy now.
记住费莱医生所说的你的心脏
Remember what Doc Frye said about that heart of yours.
我们回家后所要做的第一件事 就是要查出
Now the first thing we've got to do when we get home is find out...
那男孩是那一家的
...who that boy's proper family is.
他没有家 总之不是在这一带
He hasn't got any. Not around here, anyway.
马莎 你是否在想我以为你在想的?
Martha, Are you thinking what I think you are thinking?
我们可以说他是我们在北卡州 表兄的孩子
We could say he's the child of my cousin in North Dakota...
而现在是孤儿了
...and just now orphaned.
老马莎
Old Martha.
强纳森 他只是个孩子
Jonathan, he's only a baby.
马莎 你看到我们是怎么找到他的了
Martha, now you saw how we found him.
马莎克拉克肯  你听到我说的话了吗?
Martha Clark Kent, are you listening to what I'm saying?
强纳森
Jonathan
来吧 伙计们
Come on, gang.
那是场不错的比赛吧?
That was a great game.
好吧
All right.
快点 伙计们 快点 把你们的头帽放整齐点
Come on, hustle, let's go. Stack your helmets neatly.
记得那身制服 明天前洗干净
Remember about the uniforms, cleaned and washed...
还有看起来像是支足球队
...by tomorrow, and looking like a football team.
克拉克 全得为明天的比赛洗好
Let's have those clothes washed and ready for tomorrow's game.
看哪一个跑在最后
Got to beat Mount Vernon High.
坚持住
Hold on!
郎娜
Lana?
别麻烦这个了 我和其他装备一起拿进去
Don't bother with these. I'll take them in with the other equipment.
谢谢 克拉克 当然
- Thank you, Clark. - Sure.
听我说 我们一大群要去马丽欧兰斯
Listen, a whole bunch of us are going up to Mary Ellen's.
放些唱片 你愿意来吧?
Play some records. Would you like to come?
当然
Sure.
听起来会很好玩
Sounds like it could be a lot of fun.
海伦 他不能去 他有很多事要做
Kent can't make it. Still got a lot of work to do.
你在说些什么?我才刚叠完…
What are you talking about? I've just finished stacking...
那一些?
All that?
布莱得
Oh, Brad!
来吧 郎娜
Hey, come on, Lana.
Come on, Lana.
来吧 我们走
Come on, let's go.
- 来吧 他得清理这些 - 再见 克拉克
- He has to clean up. - 'Bye, Clark.
- 再见 郎娜  - 清干净这一塌 克拉克
- 'Bye, Lana. - Clean this up, Clark.
再见 克拉克
'Bye, Clark.
明天见 再见
See you tomorrow. Bye-bye.
看 克拉克在那
Hey, look, there's Clark!
他怎么可能在这边?
Oh, how could him here?
克拉克
Clark?
你怎么能这么快的到这的?
How did you get here so fast?
我跑来的
I ran.
跑的?
Ran, huh?
我告诉过你们他是个怪胎 我们快离开这里
Told you he was an oddball, let's get out of here.
眩耀了一下 是吧?儿子
Been showing off a bit, haven't you, Son?
我不是故意要眩耀的 爸
I didn't mean to show off, Pa.
只是那个叫布莱得的家伙 我想把他撕成碎片
It's just that guys like that Brad, I just want to tear them apart.
是 我知道 我知道
Yeah, I know.
是 我知道我不应该
Yeah, I know I shouldn't.
是 我知道你能做这些奇妙的事
Yeah, I know you can do all these amazing things...
有时你想 若不能告诉别人
...and sometimes you think that you will just go bust...
你会爆掉的
...unless you can tell people about it.
是没错
- Yeah. - That's right.
每次我打橄榄球都能触地得分的
I mean, every time I get the football I can make a touchdown.
这我确定 每一次
- That's for sure. - Every time.
我是说让别人在做的事 而他也能做
Is it showing off when somebody's doing the things he's capable of doing?
那是眩耀吗?
Is a bird showing off when it flies?
不 你听我说
No, now, you listen to me.
当你刚到我们身边时 我们认为...
When you came to us, we thought...
别人发现你所能做的事
...people would take you away...
他们会把你由我们身边带走
...when they found out the things that you do.
而那非常令我们担忧
It worried us a lot.
而当我们逐渐老了 非常的不同
Then when a man gets older and he thinks very differently.
事情也变的非常清楚
And things get very clear.
有一件事我很清楚 儿子 那就是你来这是有原因的
And there's one thing I do know, Son, and that is you are here for a reason.
我不知道谁是那个原因 或不管那原因是什么 你知道吗
I don't know whose reason, or whatever the reason is...
也许只是因为…
...maybe it's because...
我不知道 那是…
I don't know.
但我的确知道一件事 那不是触地得分的分数
But I do know one thing. It's not to score touchdowns.
谢谢 爸
Thanks, Dad.
我们跑吧
I'll race you to it. Yeah.
你会吗?来吧
You will?
来吧 爸 跑吗 来吧 跑呀
Run. Come on, come on. Move, move.
来呀 跑 加油 比赛呀 班
Go, go. Come on. Hey, Baron.
不好
Oh, no.
但…
But...
强纳森
Jonathan?
Jonathan!
爸?
Dad.
强纳森
Jonathan.
不
No.
我能做的那些事情
All those things I can do...
那些力量
...all those powers...
而我甚至救不了他
...and I couldn't even save him.
我必须走了
I have to leave.
我知道这个时刻会来的
I knew this time would come.
我们两在找到你的那一天就晓得
We both knew it from the day we found you.
我昨天和班哈
I talked to Ben Hubbard yesterday.
他说 从今以后他很乐意来帮忙
He said that he'd be happy to help out from now on.
妈
Mother!
我知道 儿子
I know, Son.
我知道
I know.
你知道…你要往那去吗?
Do you know where you're headed?
北方
North.
要记住 儿子
Remember us, Son.
永远要记住
Always remember us.
我的儿子
My son...
你不会记得我
... you do not remember me.
我是乔罗
I am Jor-El.
我是你的父亲
I am your father.
到现在 你应该己18岁了
By now you will have reached your eighteenth year...
那是在地球上的算法
... as it is measured on Earth.
在那个时刻 以你们的算法
By that reckoning...
我已经死了好几千年了
... I will have been dead for many thousands of your years.
我所拥有的
The knowledge...
生理及历史上的知识
... that I have of matters, physical and historical...
在你的新家中我会彻底传授给你
... I have given you fully on your voyage to your new home.
那是很重要的事务
These are important matters to be sure...
但事实仍然是很重要的
... but still matters of mere fact.
而你所要问的问题
There are questions to be asked...
是让你自己解答的时候到了
... and it is time for you to do so.
这里是...
Here, in this...
维护你的一座堡垒
...this fortress of solitude...
我们应该要共同去寻找解答
... we shall try to find the answers together.
所以 我的儿子
So, my son...
说话吧
... speak.
我是谁?
Who am I?
你叫做葛洛
Your name is Kal-El.
你是克莱顿星球唯一的生存者
You are the only survivor of the Planet Krypton.
即使晓得你是以人类扶养长大的 但你不是他们的一份子
Even though you were raised as a human, you are not one of them.
你有伟大的力量 只是还有一些你不确定的
You have great powers, only some of which you have...
那是你必需去发现的
... as yet discovered.
现在跟我来吧 吾儿
Come with me now, my son...
只是要突破你在地球上 所能找到的平衡
... as we break through the bars of your earthly confinement.
在时间的太空中飞行
Traveling through time and space.
在那第六…你的力量
Your powers will far exceed those of mortal men.
你禁止干预人类的历史
It is forbidden for you to interfere with human history.
宁愿放弃你的领导权力 而不能干预
Rather let your leadership stir others to.
在下一年中 我们要检视人类的人
In the next year, we shall examine the human heart.
那比它原有的样子更易碎
It is more fragile than your own.
你所超过的火焰通道 是你自己的银河系的边缘
As we pass through the flaming turmoil which is the edge of your own galaxy...
你通过了克莱顿星的红太阳边缘
... we will enter the realm of the red Krypton sun...
是你种种特殊能力的根源
... source of your strength and nourishment...
是我们祖先所留下来的方向
... and cause of our eventual destruction.
克莱顿星 吾儿
The Planet Krypton, my son...
你的家园 从前的家
... your home as it was.
今年 我们要检视议会 为了你的道德观
This year we shall examine the various concepts of immortality...
而那基本的是自然的事实
... and their basis in actual fact.
第28银河系的所有资料
The total accumulation of all knowledge spanning the 28 known galaxies...
全包容在我送在你身边的水晶里
... is embedded in the crystals which I have sent along with you.
好好的研读它 吾儿
Study them well, my son.
当你回到你自己的银河系之时
By the time you return to the confines of your galaxy...
你的12年会过去了
... twelve of your years will have passed.
但在其他的理由中的这一个
For this reason, among others...
我为你选择了地球
... I have chosen Earth for you.
现在是你加入你的新世界之时
It is now time for you to rejoin your new world...
而且为它服务 为它
... and to serve its collective humanity.
像他们中的一员般的过活 葛洛
Live as one of them, Kal-El...
去发现你的力量及威力能做什么
... and discover where your strength and your power are needed.
永远怀有一颗荣誉的心 为了特殊的职责
But always hold in your heart the pride of your special heritage.
你可以成为一个伟大的人 葛洛 我希望你是
They can be a great people, Kal-El, they wish to be.
他们只留下来光亮给你引路
They only lack the light to show the way.
在这上述所有的理由之上 他们对于善良所拥有的蓄容力
For this reason, above all, their capacity for good...
我派了你给他们
... I have sent them you...
我唯一的儿子
... my only son.
好了 到了 老兄 星球日报
Okay, this is it, mac, the Daily Planet.
新鲜水果 小姐 买点蕃茄如何
Fresh fruit! Hey, how about a tomato, lady?
新鲜水果 宝贝 你好吗?
Hey, fresh fruit and vegetables.
微笑
Smile.
喋喋不休中有几个T?
How many "T's" in "bloodletting"?
两个
Two.
你在写什么?依连小姐
What are you writing?
一个老的规律 你怎么拼大屠杀
An ode to spring. How do you spell "massacre"?
MASSACRE RE 谢谢
M-a-s-s-a-c-r-e. r-e, Thanks.
好棒 依连小姐 为何你总是能有好报导?
Golly, how come you get all the great stories?
一个好记者不会有好报导 吉米
A good reporter doesn't get great stories.
一个好记者让它们变好的
A good reporter makes them great.
主编 这是东区谋杀案的报导
Chief, here's that story on the murder case.
依我看是社会版的头 也许那再加张照片
The way I see it, it's a headline on the front page with my picture...
强奸者只有一个P 露易丝依连 见过克拉克肯
There's only one "P" in "rapist." Lois Lane, say hello to Clark Kent.
依连小姐 你好
Hello, Miss Lane, how are...
你好 吉米欧生 摄影师
How are you doing? Jimmy Olsen, photographer.
克拉克肯 幸会
Hi. Clark Kent. Nice to meet you.
这个什么都有了 性 暴力 客观的角度 我是说 你看
It's got everything: Sex, violence, the ethnic angle.I mean, look at...
是 女厕所的外国口音也是一样
So does a lady wrestler with a foreign accent.
- 肯 你能打开这个吗? - 当然 怀特先生
- Kent, can you open this? - Sure, Mr. White.
但这个能当系列报导的基本篇
This could be the basis for a series of articles:
露易丝依连报导的无理由杀划
"Making Sense of Senseless Killings" by Lois Lane.
我是说我们有心理学家 有…
We get psychologists, sociologists, interviews...
露易丝 露易丝
Lois, Lois.
你是在推销一堆一无是处的垃圾
Lois, you're pushing a bunch of rinky-dink tabloid garbage.
星球日报有它的格调在那
The Daily Planet has a tradition...
抱歉 抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
天 抱歉 我不是故意那么晃的
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to shake it up like that.
当然不是 露易丝
Of course not, Lois.
为何会有人 会想让一个陌生人出洋相呢
Why would any one want to make a total stranger look like a fool?
那个给我
I'll take that.
谢谢 抱歉 怀特先生
Thanks. I'm sorry, Mr. White.
欧生 我付你周薪40元 是要让你来这闲晃的吗?
Why do I pay you $40 a week when I should have you arrested for loitering?
- 去给…先生拿快去  - 肯
- Go get Mr... a towel. - Kent.
- 快 - 是的 主编
- Move, kid, move. - Right, Chief.
是 主编
- Make mine black, no sugar. - Right, Chief.
还有别叫我亲爱的
And don't call me sugar.
是的…亲爱的
Right... Sugar.
主编要咖啡 不加糖 我要杯柠檬茶
Chief wants coffee, no sugar. I'll take tea with lemon.
露易丝 带肯去外面见见大家
Lois, why don't you take Kent out to meet everybody, huh?
把他向大伙们介绍一下 他今天开始为报社工作
Just introduce him around. He's starting on the paper today.
我把城市新闻部份给你了
I'm giving him the City beat.
主编
Chief!
那是我的区域
That's my beat!
露易丝
Lois.
克拉克肯也许看来是个资浅记者
Lois, Clark Kent may seem like just a mild-mannered reporter...
但是听我说 他不但晓得如何适当尊敬主编
...but not only does he know how to treat his Chief with the proper respect...
他不但有一付文质彬彬的格调
...not only does he have a snappy, punchy prose style...
是我在这一行40年中 所见过最快的打字的
...but he is, in my 40 years in this business, the fastest typist I've ever seen.
抱歉
Excuse me.
这里 你忘了我的报导了
Here, you forgot my article.
打扰 怀特先生 我在想...
Excuse me, Mr. White. I was wondering...
你是否能以周做单位
...if you could arrange for half my salary...
把我半数的薪水寄去这个地址
...to be sent to this address on a weekly basis.
你的赌注 对吧?
Your bookie, right?
我的什么?
My what?
别告诉我
Don't tell me!
他每周寄薪水回去给他灰发的甜蜜母亲
He sends a check every week to his sweet, gray-haired mother.
事实上她是银发
Actually, she's silver-haired.
我看我能做些什么
I'll see what I can do.
多谢了 怀特先生
Thank you very much, Mr. White.
打扰了
Well?
家里还有人像你吗?
Any more at home like you?
不见得真有 没有
Not really, no.
我想也是
I didn't think so.
那么 到这边来给自己找张桌子
Well, get yourself a desk over here.
这里?
Over here?
是 这里有些纸 就在那边
Here, there's some paper and a file right there.
对不起
Sorry.
- 是 - 再见
- Yeah. - See you.
- 我遇到了这个很棒的男人 你知道吗? - 嘿 那太好了
- I met this really great guy, you know. - Hey, fabulous.
我们度过了美好的周末 我和他在农场里见面
We had this fabulous weekend. I met him at this dude ranch.
好像已经认识我很久了
I haven't been since I was seven.
我得去寄这些了 好的 拜拜 祝你今晚好运
- I got to mail these letters. - Good luck tonight.
克拉克 露易丝
- Hi, Clark. - Hi, Lois.
喜欢你上班的第一天吗?
How did you like your first day on the job?
这 坦白说时间比我期待的要长
The hours were sort of longer than I expected...
但还好 你知道我的意思是 遇见了你 吉米欧生 怀特先生
...but on the whole, meeting you and Jimmy Olsen and Mr. White...
在那种情况下 我说我自我陶醉
Gosh, on a whole, I'd say it's been swell.
自我陶醉?
- "Swell"? - Yup.
你知道吗?克拉克
You know, Clark...
在这世上只剩下很少数的人
...there are very few people left in the world...
在觉得舒服时会说那个字
...who feel comfortable saying that word.
那一个字? 自我陶醉
- What word? - Swell.
对我则听起来很自然
Really? I always thought it was kind of natural.
对不起  克拉克
- Sorry. - Clark.
你先 没关系的
- 对不起 露易丝 - 嘿 雷
- Sorry, Lois. - Hi, Rex.
- 今天看到什么好的吗? - 在你出现之前没有
- Did you see anything good today? - Not until you came along.
露易丝
Lois.
雷 这位是…
Rex, this is...
- 克拉克肯 - 你好 幸会
- Clark Kent. How do... - See you...
露易丝
Lois?
你要去那?
Hey, where you going?
我能帮你穿大衣吗?
Can I help you with your coat?
- 谢谢 那就行了 - 当然
- Thanks, can you get that? - Sure.
你喜欢怀特先生吗?
Did you like Mr. White?
他是个好人 吉米欧生也棒极了
He was a nice guy and Jimmy was fantastic.
嘿
Hey!
过来这
Come here.
快点...
Come on...
过来 快点过来
Get in here, hurry up. Come on.
克拉克 我想我们最好离开这里
We'd better get out of here.
我想我们最好照他说的做 露易丝
We'd better do what he says, Lois.
过来 过来 进来这里面 快点
Come on, get in here, quick.
别…别做任何事 好吗? 就是这样我来了 别这样
Don't, don't do anything. It's all right, I'm coming.
我来了
We're coming.
抱歉
Excuse me.
- 这里? - 对 对
- Here? - Yeah, yeah.
请别用那个指着我 先生 你用那可能会伤到人的
Don't point that at me, sir. You could hurt somebody with that.
好了 好了 在那别动
Okay, okay. Hold it there.
稍候一下
Just a minute.
当然我了解这些日子难过
Now I realize that...
但这并不是解决之道
...times are tough for some these days, but this isn't the answer.
你不能用枪来解决社会上的问题
You can't solve society's problems with a gun.
你知道吗?老弟 你是对的
You know, somebody, you're right.
我要转变去过新生活 对你有益 先生 那很好
- I'm going to turn over a new leaf. - Good for you. That's the spirit.
你看 他并不想伤害任何人
He doesn't really want to hurt anyone.
我抢过这位小姐的皮包之后
Right after I rip off this lady's purse.
当然
Of course!
现在 来吧 小姐 递过来
Now come on, lady, hand it over.
露易丝 我想你最好是…
Lois, I think you'd better...
露易丝 你在干什么?
Lois! What are you doing?
克拉克
Clark
克拉克 你还好吗?
Clark, Are you all right?
发生了什么事?
What happened?
我的天 我猜我一定是昏倒了 昏倒?
- Golly, I guess I must have fainted. - Fainted?
- 你昏倒了? - 抱歉
- You fainted! - I'm sorry.
好吧
Well.
真的 露易丝 万一那人开枪打你呢?
Really, Lois, supposing that man had shot you?
为了十元 你的信用卡 梳子
Is it worth risking your life over $10...
及口红去冒生命危险 值得吗?
...two credit cards, a hairbrush and a lipstick?
你是怎么晓得的? 知道什么?
- How did you know that? - Know what?
你刚正确的描述了我皮包的内容
You described the exact contents of my purse.
随便猜的
Wild guess.
计程车
Taxi!
欧帝斯
- Hey! - Hi, Otis.
那是什么?搭挡
So, what's happening, partner?
看看我们找到什么了
Look what we got.
我们抓住他
Let's take him.
且慢
Wait a minute.
也许他自己带我们去抓大头
Maybe he'll lead us to the big man himself.
赖克斯路梭?
Lex Luthor?
这次你说对了
You got it, Aramus.
我们来次午夜逮捕
We'll make Captain by midnight.
这是你会看到的 SKQ101火箭要使用了
Hey, what do you read? XK-101 rocket to be used.
这是你会看到的
Hey, what do you read?
- 麦特  - 欧帝斯
- Hey, Matt. - Hi, Otis.
只是来买份星球日报
Just getting a Daily Planet here.
好了 好了 好
Okay. All right.
好了 我付他钱 我拿了个饼
See, I'm paying him, and I got a pretzel, too.
谢了 欧帝斯
Thanks, Otis.
有多少个袋子?
How many bags, Shutzy?
这里是46巡逻组 我们在步行 通话完毕
This is Metropolis 46. We're on foot. Over and out.
我们走
Let's go.
请大家注意 请大家注意
Your attention, please.
蒙卓普斯特快车现在在上层登车
The Metropolis Flyer is now ready for departure...
在第六号轨道
... on the upper level. Track 6.
好了 他下到火车月台去了 我要去追他
He's going down on a train platform. I'm going after him.
好的 哈瑞 我呼叫支援单位 你现在起小心点 好吗?
Okay, I'll call for backup. Be careful now, will you?
好的 阿敏斯 我没事的
All right, Aramus. All right.
现在在下层登车的是…
Now boarding on the lower level...
10分钟 上冷气车  开往马利兰 普开普西
Now 10 minutes, air-conditioned cars, Mount Vernon, Poughkeepsie...
还没上者的请上车
Board now. All aboard.
最没有麻烦的交通工作 水牛城 莎尔基尔
Metropolis Transportation to Buffalo, Syracuse...
吸烟车箱在前面 请往前面走
Smoking cars are forward, move along now.
请把行李放在上面
Luggage at the top.
吸烟车箱在前面 有更多人登车 登车中
Smoking cars are forward. All aboard, boarding.
阿敏斯 阿敏斯 走22号铁轨
Aramus, Aramus, make it Track 22.
我看过他 紧跟着他  下层 第22号铁轨
I've seen him and I'm right on him. Lower level, Track 22.
原来是这么回事
So that's it!
那大脑能产生那么多能量
让那双腿移动 真是令你惊异
It's amazing that brain can generate enough power to keep those legs moving.
哈瑞
Harry...
哈瑞 你在那? 哈瑞
Harry, where are you? Harry?
不
No.
哈瑞
Harry.
有病
Sick!
有病 你真的有病
Sick, you're really sick!
有病?这个死亡的记号?
I'm sick, Ms. Teschmacher?
创造世纪最大的犯罪是有病?
Sick when we're days from executing the crime of the century?
不…不 请离开那里
No. Step away from that, please.
你如何对我们这时代最伟大罪犯 选择祝贺的用词?
How do you choose to congratulate the greatest criminal mind of our time?
你告诉我说我聪明极了
Do you tell me that I'm brilliant?
不…不 那太明显了 说我承认你
Oh, no, that would be too obvious, I grant you.
有魅力?
Charismatic?
在非常重的…
Fiendishly gifted?
试试看用扭曲的
Try twisted!
离那远一点 离开 离开
Get away from that, get away!
告诉我一件事 赖克斯
Tell me, Lex.
为何那么多人得为世纪之罪而死
Why do so many people have to die for the crime of the century?
为何?你问为什么?
Why? You ask why?
当你在浴盆里时电话响你怎么办
Why does the phone always ring when you're in the bathtub?
为何这时代最聪明的魔鬼领导者
Why is the most brilliantly diabolical leader of our time...
让他自己为白痴所围绕者?
...surrounding himself with total nincompoops?
我回来了 路梭先生
I'm back, Mr. Luthor.
是的 我正在谈到你
I was just talking about you.
你又被跟踪了
You were followed again.
又是那些像猫一般的悲伤之事
In spite of those cat-like reflexes.
- 路梭先生 路梭先生 我很抱歉 - 欧帝斯
- Mr. Luthor. Mr. Luthor.I'm sorry. - Otis.
那是我要你为我买的报纸吗?
Is that the newspaper I asked you to get me?
是的
Yes.
那么我为何没在看它呢?
Then why am I not reading it?
因为我还没交给你?
Because I haven't given it to you yet?
没错
Right.
终于 是官方的了
At last it's official.
谢谢慷慨的美国政府的协助
Thanks to the help of the US Government...
我们要成为历史上最伟大的 房地产的前锋
...we are about to be involved in the greatest real-estate swindle of all time.
赖克斯 为何
Lex, what is this...
对土地那么的狂热 永远是土地 土地 土地
...obsession with real estate? All the time, "land, land, land."
黛丝马克小姐 当我六岁时 家父对我说
Miss Teschmacher, When I was 6 years old, my father said to me...
滚出去
"Get out! "
在那个之前 他说：儿子  星星也许会升起 下沉
Before that, he said, "Son, stocks may rise and fall...
直到这些交通系统也许会崩溃
''...utilities and transportation systems may collapse...
人们没有一点的好处 但他们永远需要土地
''...people are no damn good, but they'll always need land...
经由他们的鼻子去取得它
''...they'll pay through the nose to get it."
记住家父所说的 土地
- "Remember," my father said... - "Land."
没错
Right.
他没看到我如何谦卑的开始
It's a pity that he didn't see...
建造这整个帝国 是种遗憾
...from such humble beginnings how I've created this empire.
帝国?这个?
An empire. This?
黛丝马克小姐 你认识多少女孩有像这个这样的
Miss Teschmacher,How many girls do you know have a Park Avenue address like this?
公园大道地址?在地下两百英尺?
Park Avenue address, 200 feet below?
你知道上面有多少人在争吵
Do you realize what people are shelling out up there...
只为了几间房及普通的电梯?
...for a few miserable rooms off a common elevator.
一个人还能要求些什么?
What more could anyone ask?
- 欧生
- 什么事?
- Olsen
- Yeah?
把这个马上帖在公布栏去
Get this Loch Ness update right into composing.
不 就是那样 布拉 让她上床 对
Yeah, no that's it, Roth. Put it to bed, right.
你还站在那里干什么?
Why are you standing here for?
我没有
I'm not.
我又没有要说去
- I wasn't going to say it. - Go.
性神经病的描述
The sex maniac profile.
对 看 95%的人都需要 你认为呢?
Right. Nine to five it's a Pulitzer Prize winner. What do you bet?
巴西那个字里面没有Z
There's no "Z" in "brassiere."
你在这上面表现的不错
Nice job on that union scandal, Kent.
保持你的水准谢了 怀特先生
Gosh, thanks, Mr. White.
克拉克 晚安
Hi, Clark. Good night.
这里 让我为你拿那个 多谢了
- Here, let me carry that for you. - Thanks a lot.
露易丝 你有一分钟吗?
Lois, have you got a minute?
对不起露易丝
Excuse me, please.
这两封照着信封的地址寄
And these two go to the addresses on the envelope, okay?
晚安
Good night.
我想你也许想和我共进晚餐
I was wondering if you'd have dinner with me?
抱歉 克拉克 我还有事
I'm sorry, I'm booked.
空军一号要降落在机场 这些孩子要很确定你晓得
Air Force One is landing at the airport. This kid'll be there to make sure...
他若回答你两个问题就受用不尽
...you-know-who answers the questions he would rather duck.
老天 你难道从未休息
Don't you ever let up?
休息什么?我是说我看到了
What for? I mean I've seen how the other half lives.
以我姐姐做例子 3个小孩 2只猫及一只鹦鹉
My sister, for instance. Three kids, two cats, and one mortgage.
我一星期内就会变成神经病
I would go bananas in a week.
我能送你去机场吗? 除非你会飞 否则不行
- Can I take you to the airport? - Not unless you can fly.
克拉克
Clark
女用 我要换衣服了 谢谢
"Ladies." I have to change, thank you. Goodbye.
露易丝 也许我们能…
Maybe we could...
露易丝
Lois
能帮我拿我寄了它吗? 当然谢谢
- Would you mail that for me? Thanks. - Sure.
晚安
Good night.
下去的?下去的?
Going down, please, going down.
下去的?
Going down?
往上的 往上 往上
Going up. Up, up.
晚安
Good night.
星球日报直升机一号 这里是地面中心
Daily Planet, Copter One. This is ground.
星球一号 请讲
Planet One, go ahead.
请来接依连小姐到机场去 和空军一号会面 是紧急飞行
Miss Lane is here for a ride to the airport to meet Air Force One. It's a hurry flight.
知道了 我们在路上了 已经过河了在市内了 预备运送
We're on our way over the river. Have one aboard for transfer. Over.
请回答知道了 星球一号 你可以降落 风速1022点5 温度是29度 华氏89度
Roger, Planet One. You're clear to land. Wind 0-2-0-1-5. Altimeter 2-9-8-9.
知道了 通话完毕
Roger, Over and out.
没有作用 你能控制住它吗?
A malfunction, can't get lift off.
控制不住怎么回事?怎么回事
- You've hooked a cable. - What's happening?
下坠了 下坠了
Set it down.
地面控制中心 我不能控制它了
My God, we've lost motor control.
我不能…
I can't hold it.
我控制不住它 我控制不住
人们卧倒 人们卧倒
He's lost it.
醒来
Wake up.
救命 …救命
Help!
退后 退后
Step back, folks.
好了 请大家退后 离开街上
Get back. Move over to the other side of the street.
好了 好了 把摄影机带到这来 好了 往上拍
Bring the canvas here. Get it up there.
看到上面的直升机吗?
There's a helicopter up there.
救我
Help me.
好了 我们动作快一点
All right, folks. Let's move back.
让前锋到这里面来
Let these firemen get in here.
救我 救命
Help me!
停在那 退后
Hold it. Get back.
好了 别往前 好了 退后
Get off the street, folks.
快点 往后退
这不是什么好玩的
快点 排成一
快点 别让人群越过这
好了 把人们由街道上赶开
让大家离开街道上 快点 叫他们离开 快点  快点 到建筑物里面去
All right, get along there. Get away from the side of the building.
别让大家挤成一团 快点 快点
Hold these crowds back. Move.
救我 救我
Help!
说吧 吉姆
Say, Jim...
失陪
Excuse me.
那装扮有够烂
That's a bad outfit.
好了 把人群驱散
Okay, move these people.
看来是要摔死了
My God! Look up there.
那是什么?
What the hell's that?
别紧张 小姐 我接着你了
Easy, miss. I've got you.
你接住我了 谁接住你呢了?
You've got me? Who's got you?
我不敢相信 我只是不敢相信 他接住她了
I can't believe it, I just cannot believe it. He got her.
各位 这个人需要帮忙
Gentlemen, this man needs help.
好了 希望这小事没让你怕飞行 小姐
I hope this little incident hasn't put you off flying, miss.
实际上来说 当然 那依然是旅行最安全的方法
Statistically speaking, of course, it's still the safest way to travel.
没错
Right.
等一下
Wait!
你是谁?
Who are you?
一位朋友
A friend.
再见
'Bye.
你好 电梯有什么不对了吗?
Something wrong with the elevator?
往下?
Going down?
不
No.
警员先生
Officer.
警员先生 晚安慕尼
Good evening, Officer Mooney.
他们说忏悔对灵魂有益
They say confession is good for the soul.
我会听听这个人的 把他带走
I'd listen to this man. Take him away.
歹徒在河滨区
快点 我们离开这里
Come on, let's get out of here.
动作快点 快呀 快呀
Move your ass! Come on!
好了 我们走 我们走
Okay, let's go. Let's go.
放下你们的武器  放下你们的武器
Drop your weapons. Drop your weapons.
胡说 快点 我们离开这里
Bullshit! Come on, let's get out of here.
好了 站住 站在那别动
Okay, hold it. Hold it right there.
好了 别动 土蛋们别开枪
Okay, freeze, you turkeys.
别激动 你抓到我们了
- Don't shoot! - Keep your cool. You got us.
喜欢振动?
Bad vibrations?
警佐 你不相信我 我发誓 在飞
Sergeant, you don't believe me. I swear it, flying.
穿红披风蓝衣服
With a big red cape and bright red boots as well.
怎么回事?慕尼想想他去那 又再飞回空中像只大蓝鸟
Quick as a wink he was gone. He flew up in the air again, he did, like a big blue bird.
- 像只大蓝鸟? - 你不相信我
- A big blue bird? - You don't believe me!
还有蓝波浪线?
With bright red boots?
飞进来的
Take the night off.
你为何不今晚休息回墨菲酒吧去
Go back to Murphy's bar and continue what you started.
我还有几分钟然后亲自去那找你
I'll be off in a few minutes and I'll meet you there.
慕尼
Mooney.
第一瓶酒我请 让我去拿帽子
The first bottle's on me. Let me get my hat.
布斯基 你能由上面下来吗?
Frisky, will you come down from there.
嘿 我来抓它
Hi. I'll get him.
来吧 没关系的
Come on, it's all right.
- 来了 小姐 - 谢了 先生
- Here you go, miss. - Gee, thanks, mister.
不客气
Nothing.
拜拜 布斯基
Goodbye, Frisky. So long now.
再见了
'Bye.
妈 妈 布斯基卡在树上
Mommy, Mommy, Frisky was stuck in the tree.
那个人由天上飞下来把它给了我
Then this man swooped out of the sky and gave him to me.
我是否告诉过你别再说谎话?
Haven't I told you to stop telling lies.
查布罗机场 这是空军一号 是否能告知最新的气象报告?
Metropolis Airport, this is Air Force One. Could we have the latest weather report?
主要城市目前天气状况是多云...
Metropolis currently ceiling 500, overcast 700 broken...
会有小雨 风速240到250 风向9到9点8度知道了
... visibility one half in showers. Wind 2-4-0-2-5. Altimeter 9-0-9-8.
收到
Roger.
这个 看来不太好 你认为呢?
Doesn't look good. What do you think?
怎么回事?发生了什么事? 一号马达的动力失去
- What the hell was that? - You've lost power in number one.
失去动力?见鬼 我们失去了整个马达
Lost power? We've lost the whole engine.
一号马达不见了  把一号马达关闭
- Pressure's going. - Shut down number one.
关闭一号马达加强2 3号
Bring up two and three.
我们的压力在下降中
We haven't got enough pressure to keep going.
紧急求救 紧急求救 查布罗塔台 这是空军一号
Mayday, mayday. Metropolis tower. Air Force One.
我们失去了一个马达 并且在失速中
We have lost port outboard engine and part of wing.
要求紧急降落?位置在那里?
Request emergency landing. What's the position?
查布罗机场西南方十哩处
Ten miles southwest of Metropolis Airport.
告诉他们总统在飞机上
Notify them the President's on board.
位置是查布罗机场西南方十哩
Present position 10 miles, that's 10 miles southwest of Metropolis Airport.
方向是306度 高度6千尺
Heading: 3-0-5, height: 6,000 feet.
怎么回事?我们的马达回来了?
What the hell happened? We got our engine back?
那外面是怎么回事?
What the hell's going on out there?
飞吧 别看 飞就对了
Fly, don't look, just fly.
我们有某种东西
We got something.
我不说那是什么 只管信任我
I'm not saying what it is, just trust me.
报告近来说 对空军一号的奇迹式救援
Reports are coming in of a miraculous saving of Air Force One...
那正是我在心里所说的
... from almost certain destruction...
在星球日报大楼救援露易丝依连 只用了一只手
... rescuing Miss Lois Lane, reporter from the Daily Planet, with one hand...
而另一只抓住了坠毁的直升机
... and a crashed helicopter with the other.
又有了某一类奇妙的希望
... some sort of fantastic hoax.
你的猜想和别人的一样好 那究竟是奇迹还是假的呢?
Your guess is as good as anybody's. True or false?
是奇迹还是欺骗?这个回答...
Miracle or fraud? The answer...
- 黛丝马克小姐  - 男人还是神话?
- Miss Teschmacher! - Man or myth?
关掉
Turn it off.
赖克斯
Lex.
对这个人的报导 你认为是真的吗?
What's the story on this guy? Do you think it's the genuine article?
若他是 他不是这世界上的人
If he is, he's not from this world.
为什么?
Why?
因为任何能给予人类奇妙希望的 那会是我
If any human being was gonna perpetrate such a hoax, it would have been me!
欧帝斯
Otis.
我的浴袍
My robe.
马上来 路梭先生
Right away, Mr. Luthor.
你知道 总之我在想 他是来这搅局的
It all fits somehow, this coming here to Metropolis...
在这个特别的时间
...and at this particular time.
那是种残酷的真理
There's a kind of cruel justice about it.
我是说要完成世纪之罪的人 自然也想面对世纪之挑战
To commit the crime of the century, a man wants to face the challenge of the century.
听我说 路梭先生 也许这个会飞的人只是经过而己 你知道吗?
Listen, maybe this guy that flies is just sort of passing through. You know?
经过?
Passing through?
不是在你的生命中 欧帝斯
Not on your life, Otis...
另外我很遗憾的要做牺牲
...which I would gladly sacrifice by the way...
那个摧毁他所代表的一切的机会
...for the opportunity of destroying everything that he represents.
另外 欧帝斯 下一次等我出池子后 再为我穿上浴袍
And, Otis, by the way, next time put my robe on after I'm out of the pool.
现在 看着
Now look.
邮报…它会飞
The Post, "lt Flies."
新闻报…看 妈 没有钢缆
The News, "Look, Ma, No Wires."
时报…蓝色炸弹困扰查布罗
The Times, "Blue Bomb Buzzes Metropolis."
星球日报 我们坐在这世纪报导之上
The Planet. We're sitting on top of the story of the century here.
我要那会飞的人的姓名
I want the name of this flying whatchamacallit...
出现在星球日报上就像是熏肉蛋
...to go with the Daily Planet like bacon and eggs...
香肠与豆子 死亡与收税 政治与崩溃
...franks and beans, death and taxes, politics and corruption.
我不认为他会降落下来
I don't think that he'd...
让我们达成 怀特先生
...lend himself to any cheap promotion schemes.
你是怎么晓得的?肯
Exactly how would you know that?
只是第一印象
Just first impression.
谁在说低价了? 必要的话我请他当合伙人
Who's talking cheap? I'll make him a partner if I have to.
- 对吧? - 对 主编
- Right? - Right, Chief.
我要真实的报导
I want the real story.
我要这个人的内幕资料
I want the inside dope on this guy.
他是否有家人?他住在哪? 那S代表了什么?
Has he got a family? Where does he live? What does the "S" stand for?
今晚八点 你的地方 一位朋友
他是怎么飞的?一位朋友
汤尼?他是谁? 麦克?他叫什么名字?
Tony, who is he? Mike, what's his name?
他的披风底下藏了什么?
What's he got hidden under that cape? Batteries?
一定有原因 他为何昨晚露面?
Why did he show up last night?
尼克?他是打那来的?
Where does he come from?
他是否有女友?
Does he have a girlfriend?
他最喜欢的球队是一队?肯
What's his favorite ball team, Kent?
现在听我说 我告诉你们这些男的 女的
Now listen to me, I tell you, boys and girls...
不管是你们那一个能采访到
...whichever one of you gets it out of him...
这会是自上帝和摩西说话之后
...is going to wind up with the single, most important interview since...
最重要的一个采访
...God talked to Moses!
你们都还站在这干什么?
What are you standing around about for? Move!
快去 采访那个新闻
Get on that story.
八点 他说八点 好一个朋友
"8:00," he said. Some friend!
毁灭了我的生命 像我有如尘土
That's the story of my life, "Cinderella Bites The Dust! "
晚安 依连小姐
Good evening, Miss Lane.
抱歉 你今晚有计划了吗?
Did you have plans this evening?
这一切?没有
This old thing? No.
听我说 待会再来没有问题
- I could come back later. - No!
不要 别动
Don't move.
你当然可以动
Sure you can move.
只是别飞走 好吗?
Just don't fly away, all right?
抱歉这样子唐突来此 依连小姐 但是我在想 你知道
Sorry to drop in on you like this, but I've been thinking.
世人一定对我有许多疑问 想知道答案
There must be some questions people'd like to know the answers to.
当然
Yes.
你真的不该抽烟 依连小姐
You really shouldn't smoke.
别告诉我 肺癌 对吧?
Don't tell me. Lung cancer, right?
这个 谢天谢地 还没有
Well, not yet, thank goodness.
要不要来杯酒?
Would you like a glass of wine?
不 谢了 我飞行时从不喝酒
No, thanks. I never drink when I fly.
漂亮的地方
Nice place.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们能开始采访了吗?
Shall we get started with the interview?
谢谢
Thank you.
好了 我们由基本情况先开始 你结婚了吗?
Let's start with your vital statistics. Are you married?
没有 我没有
No, I'm not.
你有女朋友吗?
Do you have a girlfriend?
不 我没有 若我有
No, I don't. But...
你会是第一个知道的
If I did, you'd be the first to know about it.
你多大了?
How old are you?
超过21岁了
Over 21.
我知道了 你不要任何人知道有多大 好
I get it. You don't want anyone to know.
你有多大?多高
And how big are you? How tall are you?
大约6尺4寸
About 6' 4''.
6尺4寸 你有多重
6' 4''. And how much do you weigh?
大约225磅
Around 225.
2…225磅?
225?
那么…
Well, ah...
我假设…
I assume then that...
你其他的身体功能都是正常的
...the rest of your bodily functions are normal?
抱歉 请再说一次
I beg your pardon?
那么我用字来说
Well, putting it delicately...
你…
...do you...
吃东西吗?
...eat?
是的 我吃东西 当我饿的时候
Yes, I do, when I'm hungry.
你吃东西? 你当然吃东西
You do. Of course, you do.
那么…那么…
Well, then is it true...
你是否真的能看透一切东西?
...that you can see through anything?
是的 我可以 蛮清楚的
Yes, I can, pretty much.
而且你完全不会感到痛
And that you're totally impervious to pain?
到目前为止
Well, so far.
我穿的内衣是什么颜色的?
What color underwear am I wearing?
抱歉 令你受窘 是不是?
I'm sorry. Did I embarrass you?
- 没有 - 我真是的
- No. - I did.
不 一点也不  只是这花盆一定是铅做的
No, it's just that this planter must be made of lead.
是 它是 所以呢?
Yes, it is. So?
你知道吗?我看透那个有点问题
I sort of have a problem seeing through lead.
那倒很有趣
That's interesting.
看透铅有问题
Problems with lead.
你有名字吗? 你是说像是劳夫那一类的?
- Do you have a first name? - Like Ralph, or something?
不 不 我是说像是… 粉红色的
- No, I mean like... - Pink.
粉红色的
Pink!
抱歉 依连小姐 我不是做意要使你受窘的
Sorry. I didn't mean to embarrass you.
你没令我受窘
You didn't embarrass me.
你的背景是什么?在哪成长的?
What's your background? Where are you from?
事实上那蛮难解释的
It's kind of hard to explain, actually.
你知道吗?我来自… 蛮远的地方
You see, I'm from... Well, from pretty far away.
事实上是另一个银河系 我来自一个叫克莱顿的星球
Another galaxy, as a matter of fact. I come from a planet called Krypton.
克莱顿
Krypton.
克莱顿 是CRI…
Cripton! With a C-r-i...
不 克莱顿事实上是KRYPT0N
No, actually it's Krypton, with a K-r-y-p-t-o-n.
KRY你喜欢粉红色吗?
Do you like pink?
我非常喜欢粉红色 欧帝斯
I like pink very much.
为什么是你?
Why are you?
什么?
Sorry?
我是说你为什么在这里? 你在这一定有原因
I mean, why are you here? There must be a reason for you to be here.
是的 我在这是要以美国方式 为真理及正义战斗
Yes, I'm here to fight for truth and justice and the American way.
你为以和这国家 每一个民选的政府战斗做结束
You'll end up fighting every official in this country.
你当然不是当真的 欧帝斯
You don't really mean that.
- 我不敢相信这个 - 欧帝斯
- I don't believe this. - Lois?
我从来不说谎
I never lie.
另外你飞的有多快?
How fast do you fly, by the way?
我真的不知道 从未费时去测验过
I don't know. I've never actually bothered to time myself.
不知道这样吧
Say?
我们为何不去弄清楚?
Why don't we find out?
你提议我们怎么做?
And how do you propose we do that?
和我一起飞一会? 你是说我可以飞?
- Take a ride with me. - You mean I could fly?
不 事实上飞由我负责 那没有关系
I'd be handling the flying, if that's okay.
这真的是太棒了 等一下 你要去哪?
- This is utterly fantastic. - Wait a minute. Where are you going?
你是当真的?当然
- Are you serious? - Sure.
怎么了?你不想去?
Don't you want to go?
好吗?不需要这些了
You won't need these.
我需要…一件毛衣 上面一定蛮凉的 不 你会够暖和的
- I need a sweater. It must be kind of... - No, you'll be warm enough.
你预备好了吗?
Ready?
克拉克说你只是某些人的幻想
Clark said that you were just a figment of somebody's imagination.
像是小飞侠
Like Peter Pan.
克拉克?他是谁?你的男友?
Clark, who's that? Your boyfriend?
克拉克?他不是什么 他只是… - 小飞侠?
- Clark? No, he's nothing. - Peter Pan?
小飞侠只适合小孩子 露易丝 那是神话
Peter Pan flew with children, Lois. In a fairy tale.
你能看穿我的心灵吗?
Can you read my mind?
你知不知道这是什么?
能怎么对我吗?
Do you know what it is that you do to me?
我不知道你是谁
I don't know who you are.
只是位由其他星星来的朋友
Just a friend from another star.
我在这像个在上学的小孩
Here I am, like a kid out of school.
和上帝牵着手
Holding hands with a god.
我是个傻子
I'm a fool.
你看看我
Will you look at me?
在发抖
Quivering.
像个小女孩 在发抖
Like a little girl shivering.
你可以看透我
You can see right through me.
你能看穿我的心灵吗?
Can you read my mind?
你能把我在想的事凑成幅景象吗
Can you picture the things I'm thinking of?
奇怪你为何是这样的
Wondering why you are...
你是所有的好事情的共同聚合
... all the wonderful things you are.
你会飞
You can fly.
你属于天空
You belong in the sky.
你和我…
You and I...
可以属于彼此
... could belong to each other.
若是你需要一位朋友
If you need a friend...
我是能陪你飞的
... l'm the one to fly to.
若是你需要被爱
If you need to be loved...
我就在这里
... here I am.
看穿我的心灵吧
Read my mind.
我想我们忘了时间了
We forgot to time ourselves.
那么 也许下次吧
Maybe next time.
你没事吧?
You okay?
那么 晚安了
Good night.
晚安
好一个超人
What a super man!
超人
Superman!
露易丝
Lois.
有人在家吗?
Anybody home? Hello?
露易丝
Lois.
- 我能进来吗? - 可以
- Hi. Can I come in? - Oh, yeah.
露易丝 我的老天  你没听到我在敲门?
For goodness' sake, didn't you hear me knocking?
露易丝 我们今晚有约会 记得吗?
We did have a date tonight, remember?
露易丝 你没有在…
You haven't been...?
没有 没有 的确希望你没有 那么 我们走吧 好吗?
I should certainly hope not. Well, let's push off, shall we?
我最好去拿外套 也许会感冒 稍候好的
I'd better get a coat. It might be cold out.
不 我是说我需要皮包 整理我的头发
I mean, I need a purse, and I have to fix my hair...
擦点腮红
...put some blush on.
露易丝
Lois.
有件事我必须告诉你 我真的是…
There's something I have to tell you. I'm really...
我是说我开始时对今晚很紧张
I was at first really nervous about tonight.
然后我决定 管他的 我要让你有一生中难得的经验
But then I decided, darn it, I was going to show you the time of your life.
那是克拉克很好
That's Clark nice.
我在想也许我们能去吃汉堡 或是任何你想做的
We could go for a hamburger or whatever you want to do.
（我和超人共度了一夜）
（露易丝依连独家专访）
现在…
Now then...
规定他提到的星系准确的位置
...given the exact location of the galaxy that he mentions...
可能有他们自己的太阳系
...and the proximity to our own solar system...
那真的太奇妙了 太奇妙了
It's amazing. Amazing!
好的不像是真的
Too good to be true.
好的不像是真的 他6尺4寸高 黑发碧眼
It's too good to be true. 6' 4", black hair, blue eyes...
不抽烟不喝酒而且说实话
...doesn't drink or smoke and tells the truth.
黛丝马克小姐
Miss Teschmacher.
有人能看战争与和平
Some people can read War and Peace...
而把它看成单纯的冒险故事
...and think it was an adventure story.
有人能看口香糖的包装纸
Others can read the ingredients on a gum wrapper...
而破解宇宙的连锁
...and unlock the secrets of the universe.
赖克斯 口香糖和宇宙的连锁 又有什么关系?
Lex, what has chewing gum got to do with the secrets of the universe?
对的 对的 黛丝马克小姐
Right, Miss Teschmacher.
以及…以及
"N."
M 你要M部份?路梭先生 马上就到
"M"? You want "M," Mr. Luthor? Coming right up.
好了 到了 M部份
So there you go, "M."
M是代表神经病
"M" as in "moron," Otis? No.
不 不 不 是N N是尼安德塔人
It's "N" as in "Neanderthal''...
笨人 低贱的人 而L是梯子
..."nincompoop," "nitwit," and "L" as in "ladder."
是 梯子 路梭先生 马上来
Here's a ladder, coming right up.
我只是没看...
I didn't see...
我很抱歉 路梭先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Luthor.
在专访中说克莱顿星…
In the interview he says that the Planet Krypton...
1948年爆炸了
...exploded in 1948.
那荒谬的怪谈
That ridiculous little freak...
花了三年陨石才到达地球
...took three years in a rocket to get to earth.
- 这里开始了 - 这里开始了
- Ergo... - Ergo.
1948年 花了三年…
Ergo 1948, that's three years on.
他身高6尺4寸 你知道吗?
He's 6' 4", you know that?
你知道为何两百这数字 和你我都有关系吗?
Do you know why the number 200 is so vitally descriptive to both you and me?
是你的体重与我的智商
It's your weight and my I.Q.
现在 人们 想想看 想想看
Think, people, think.
综合那些理由 那是那游戏之名
Deductive reasoning. That's the name of the game.
克莱顿星的物质在爆炸时
Fragments from the Planet Krypton...
进入了外太空
...exploded and went into outer space.
假设其中的部分...
It is reasonable to assume...
坠落在地球是有道理的...that some of those particles of debris
drifted to Earth.
陨石
Meteorites!
在阿利斯阿拉巴发现一块陨石
A meteorite found in Addis Ababa?
我知道我要因此到山上走一遭 但是…
I know I'll get rapped in the mouth for this, but...
又怎么样?
...so what?
你是说对我们它只是块陨石
So what? You mean to us they're just meteorites.
很公平
Fair enough.
但它的辐射线的水准是那么高
But the level of specific radioactivity...
这东西对来自克莱顿的人而言
...is so high to anyone from the Planet Krypton...
是致命物质
...this substance is lethal.
等一下 路梭先生
Wait a minute, Mr. Luthor.
你是说火与子弹不能伤到这家伙
Fire and bullets can't hurt this guy...
而这里的这个东西…
...but this stuff here...
会杀了他
...will kill him.
和我待在同一间房里
Doesn't it give you a kind of...
对你们不是种震惊或电击吗?
...a shudder of electricity through you to be in the same room with me?
不会比你试着把那块石头 装到他身上时更震惊
Not like the shudder you'll get when you lay that rock on him.
你以他的千里眼能看到 你从几哩路以外来了
He can see you coming for miles with those super peepers of his.
我的天  你给了他们双眼但却看不见
O Lord, you gave them eyes, but they cannot see...
即使是超人也不能看透铅
...nor can Superman, through lead.
他不能看透铅
He can't see through lead?
而克莱顿的陨石会毁灭他
And Kryptonite will destroy him.
有任何问题吗?学生们
Any questions, class?
不知道在阿利斯阿拉巴穿着什么
I wonder what they're wearing in Addis Ababa?
看起来像是僧袍 你知道…
Looks like a burnoose.
我们走 要24…
It's just a wraparound.
我们要去阿利斯阿拉巴? 路梭先生
Are we going to Addis Ababa, Mr. Luthor?
母鸟对飞弹运输队 请回答
Mother Bird to Missile Convoy, over.
这是运输队对母鸟 请讲
Missile Convoy to Mother Bird, go ahead.
一切看起来都很好 基地见了 通话完毕
Everything looks good, see you at the base. Over and out.
知道了 母鸟 通话完毕
Roger, Mother Bird. Over and out.
看看这个
Look at this!
蛮严重的
Looks pretty bad.
最好量一下她的脉博
Take her pulse.
好了 用无线电叫辆救护车来
Get an ambulance down here.
我不想把全部的人都挡在这里
I don't want to hold this convoy up more than I have to.
她呼吸有困难 长官 你认为呢
She's having trouble breathing. What do you think?
我建议给她做点胸部按摩
I suggest a vigorous chest massage.
再做…口对口人工呼吸
If that doesn't work, mouth-to-mouth.
是的 长官
Yes, sir!
中士 我不会让我的人 做任何我不会亲自做的事
I won't have my men do anything I wouldn't be prepared to do myself.
是 但是 长官去叫救护车
Get an ambulance.
好了 弟兄们 靠在一起
Gather around.
向后转
Turn around!
嗨
Hi.
有人受伤了吗?
Somebody hurt?
我办到了 路梭先生
I did it, Mr. Luthor.
真是太爽了 我办到了
Miss Teschmacher, I did it.
如同你所告诉我的 好了 欧帝斯 好了
- Just like you told me. - All right, Otis.
欧帝斯听我说 不是我不信任你 但是…
It isn't that I don't trust you, but...
我不信任你 欧帝斯你做了什么
I don't trust you, Otis. What did you do?
我将第一组导向器
I set the first directional vector...
设定在38上
...to 38.
第二组67 而第三组在117上
The second one to 67. And the third one to 117.
那第四组呢?
What about the fourth one?
什么第四组?
What fourth one?
且慢 且慢 第三组是117?
Wait a minute. The third one to 117?
- 是的 我把它写下来了 路梭先生 - 欧帝斯
- Yes. See, I wrote it down, Mr. Luthor. - Otis!
第三组应该是11 第四组是7
The third one was supposed to be 11, and the fourth one, 7.
哦 路梭先生
Oh, gee, Mr. Luthor.
我想是我的手臂不够长 你看
I guess my arm wasn't long enough, see.
欧帝斯 你想要有长手臂吗?
Would you like to see a long arm?
欧帝斯 你想要有很长的手臂吗
Otis, would you like to see a very, very, long arm?
不 不 路梭先生
No, Mr. Luthor.
- 好了 弄对它 行吗? - 是的 路梭先生
- All right. Get it right. - Yes, Mr. Luthor.
麦克唐诺 我以为你告诉我
I thought you told me this road would be blocked off?
- 考布劳斯基 这 - 我不是问他 是问你
- Jablowsky, didn't I tell you... - I didn't ask him, I asked you.
好了 跟我来 跟我来
All right. Follow me, men.
把那东西倒出路面去  把那东西倒离此地
Back that thing off the road. Back it off the road.
好了 听着 你必须调头回去 我没时间和你争执
You'll have to circle back. I don't have time to argue.
你开回你来的地方 行吗?
It's a heck of a day, isn't it?
那是12号道路
Route 12.
12号道路 那是在那后面 不是吗?不 长官 在那上面
- Route 12? That's back there. - No, sir, it's up there.
你确定吗?你们是打那来的?
中士 我们转错弯了 我是上尉 你在和海军军官说话
- Sergeant, we took the wrong road. - I'm a Lieutenant. A Naval Officer.
闭嘴 现在12号道路在哪条路后面了
Shut up! Now Route 12 is back that way.
这个人有糖尿病 你知道吗?
This man is a diabetic, you see.
如同你所知 我们的星球日报社 对那便宜的地价觉得很有趣
As you know, the Daily Planet is very interested in that dam...
但是我所不了解的是
...but what I don't understand...
你为何会卖给一个素未谋面之人
...is why you'd sell out to a faceless person you've never met?
我是说你甚至不知他的姓名
You don't know his name.
在他对这一无用处的沙漠
At the stupid high price he offered...
所开出来那么离谱的高价之后
...for this worthless piece of desert...
我希望它是坏地方
...I hope it's Custer!
好极了 那正是我所需的 谢谢
Perfect, just what I need. Thank you.
由火箭的那个方向打 地面是
Reporting live from the launch site, ground zero.
今天 美国政府要试射
Today marks a historic occasion since...
两枚SK101火箭
... two XK-101 rockets will be launched simultaneously.
一枚由陆军发射 另一枚由海军发射
One by the Army, and one by the Navy.
大家好 今天有人看到露易丝在附近吗?
Hi, everybody. Has anybody seen Lois today?
没 我没看见他 但主编要见你
No, but the Chief wants to see you.
你挡住电视 克拉克
You're blocking the set, Clark.
抱歉 吉尔伯 茱蒂今天好吗?
Sorry, Gil. How's Judy today? Okay?
很好 好极了
Good. Great.
打扰 怀特先生
Excuse me, Mr. White.
- 你找我? - 先生 你今天看到露易丝了吗?
You wanted to see me, sir? Have you seen Lois today?
她到西部去查件土地买卖的事
She's out West, looking into a land-fraud deal.
欧生和她在一块 出第一次任务
I sent young Olsen with her on his first assignment.
有一个未经证实身份的小丑 在那里用惊人的价钱
Some unidentified clown is buying thousands of acres...
在购买几千亩无用的沙漠
...of worthless desert at incredible prices.
那似乎没什么道理
That doesn't seem to make sense.
这世界没什么道理 肯 到现在你应该已经晓得了
The world doesn't make sense. You ought to know that.
看看这个由阿利斯阿拉巴拍来的
Look at this dispatch from Addis Ababa.
前一天晚上有人侵入博物馆 杀死了两个人 但拿走了什么?
People break into a museum at night, kill two people, and what do they take?
一块毫无价值的陨石 那你怎么想?
A worthless piece of meteorite. How do you figure that?
这个 坦白说
Well, frankly...
我无法了解任何形态的暴力
I've never been able to understand violence.
怀特先生我了解你那一点 肯
I know that about you.
那是我要和你谈谈的另一个原因
That's why I wanted to talk to you.
我在这新闻的游戏中待了40年 孩子
I've been in this news game 40 years man and boy...
我到达我现在的地位 凭藉的是胆量 怜惜 冲劲活力
...and I got where I am with guts, compassion...
及某些在你缺乏的东西 孩子
...elbow grease and something you're sadly lacking in, son.
谦虚?
Humility?
不 不是谦虚 你有一大袋谦虚
Not humility, you've got bags of humility.
进取及信心 那才是成功之钥
Aggression, confidence, that's the ticket.
发号施令 让人们知道你是谁
Take charge. Let people know who you are.
我是赖克斯
This is Lex Luthor.
只有一样活着的不是四 而能听到这种频率的人声
Only one thing alive with less than four legs can hear this frequency.
那就是你
That's you.
大约再过五分钟 一座含有氢化物的毒气制造工厂
In five minutes, a poisoned gas pellet containing propane lithium compound...
会释放出两千单位到城市中去
... will be released through thousands of air ducts in this city...
非常的有 半个查布罗市的人口会
... effectively annihilating half the population of Metropolis.
我在我多数的朋友还是影印小弟 我就已经是记者了
I was a reporter before most of my friends were copy boys.
我想让露易丝介绍超人让你认识
I want you to get Lois to introduce you to Superman.
去查出来他是谁 他喜欢什么? 那蓝色的衣服里有什么?
Find out who he is. Where did he get that blue suit?
是用什么做的?丝吗?塑胶?
Did he have it made? Is it silk? Is it plastic?
我知道对你的健康没什么影响
I know it all seems a bit much...
但是我要见你 超人
... but how else was I going to meet you, Superman?
我知道你从不能拒绝喝茶的邀请
I knew you'd never accept an invitation to tea.
还有灾难 人们有危险 人们需要帮助
But a disaster, with people in danger, people who need help...
天 我知道你就是无法抗拒  那就像是你的罩门
I just knew you couldn't resist that chance to sort of pitch in.
明白我的意思吗?
You know what I mean?
身强体壮对你很好 超人
There's a strong streak of good in you, Superman.
但没有人是十全十美的
But then nobody's perfect.
几乎没有人是
Almost nobody.
- 哦 超人 - 天啊
- Oh, Superman! - Gee!
请退后 退后 没事 别担心
Stand back, please. Nothing to get worried about.
华特 别光坐在那 下车
Don't sit there like a numskull, get out!
我想是他来了 路梭先生
I think he's coming, Mr. Luthor.
他绝对是来了 路梭先生
He's definitely coming, Mr. Luthor.
门是开着的 请进
It's open, come in.
我的律师会因门的损坏和你连络
My attorney will be in touch with you about the damage to the door.
欧帝斯 侍候他脱披风
Otis, take the gentleman's cape.
我不认为他想我去弄 路梭先生
I don't think he wants me to, Mr. Luthor.
好了 路梭 毒气工厂在那里?
Where's the gas pellet?
在某个地方
Somewhere.
事实上是在我的脑海里
It's in the back of my mind, actually.
那只是我的一个主意
It's a little idea I was toying with.
那是让你那样的聪明大脑得到灵感的方法?
Is that how a warped brain like yours gets its kicks?
一个让无辜的人死亡的计划
By planning the death of innocent people?
我造成无辜的人死亡
By causing the death of innocent people.
发射
Fire!
海鸟号 我们发射成功了
Navy Bird, we have a good launch.
海军导弹...
Navy missile...
现在 我必须说 不管你知不知
As you may or may not know, I am, as they say...
我在房地产上投资颇大
...very heavy into real estate.
在那一行想要挣钱 你就得低买高卖 对吧?
To make money, you have to buy for a little and sell for a lot, right?
对
Right.
所以 问题是?
So, the problem?
在你买卖之间 如何使土地...
How to make the land more valuable between the time you buy it...
更有价值?
...and the time you sell it?
这里是加州
Now this is California.
是合众国中最受欢迎的州
The richest, most populous state in the Union.
我不必向你上地理课 路梭
I don't need a geography lesson from you.
是的 你当然去过那 我的确忘了你能到处跑 对吧?
Of course, you've been there. I do forget, you get around, don't you?
我说到那了?
Where was I?
- 加州 - 加州 对的
- California. - California, right.
圣安得烈斯断层 也许你听说过
The San Andreas Fault, maybe you've heard of it?
是的 是两块大陆接合之处
Yes. It's the joining together of two land masses.
那是加州常常有地震的原因
The fault line is shifting, which is why you get earthquakes in California.
太好了 我自己也不能说的更好
Wonderful! Couldn't have said it better myself.
任何在此线以西的东西 是世上最富有最昂贵的房地产
Everything west of this line is the richest, most expensive real estate in the world.
圣地牙哥 洛杉矶 旧金山
San Diego, Los Angeles, San Francisco.
在这
Everything on this side of the line...
毫无价值的沙漠
...is just hundreds of miles of worthless desert land...
刚巧拥有人是…
...which just happens to be owned by...
赖克斯路梭企业
Lex Luthor Incorporated.
现在 叫我愚笨的 不负责任的
Now, call me foolish, call me irresponsible.
对我而言 五百万吨的炸弹
It occurs to me that a 500-megaton bomb...
计划落在适当的点
...planted at just the proper point would...
会毁灭了大半个加州
Would destroy most of California.
数百万无辜的人会死于非命 我们所知道的西岸会…
Millions of people would be killed and the West Coast as we know it would...
沉入海底 再见 加州
Fall into the sea. Bye-bye, California.
哈罗 新的西岸 我的西岸
Hello, new West Coast. My West Coast.
赖克斯海岸 路梭维尔
Costa Del Lex, Luthorville.
马瑞娜达拉斯 欧帝斯堡
Marina Del Lex, Otisburg.
欧帝斯堡?
"Otisburg"?
黛丝马克小姐的区域 她把她的范围切一些给我
Miss Teschmacher, she's got her own place.
欧帝斯堡?
"Otisburg"?
是一个小小的地方
It's a little bitty place.
欧帝斯堡?
Otisburg?
好 我把它擦掉 如此而己
I'll just wipe it off, that's all.
你是个梦想者 赖克斯路梭
You're a dreamer, Lex Luthor.
恶心的 扭曲的梦想者  你的计划根本不可能行的通
A sick, twisted dreamer. Your plan couldn't possibly work.
我承认我们有几个问题
I'll admit there were a few problems.
但只是绝对无误的着弹点
Adjusting the precise trajectory of the missile.
找到断层本身的压力点
Finding the optimum stress point for the fault line itself...
顺便一提 它就是…
...which, by the way, is target zero. Right...
就在…这里
...here.
那是不可能的
That's impossible!
发生了什么事?上尉
What's happening, Lieutenant?
导航系统失控 长官
Trajectory malfunction, sir.
引爆
Abort.
所有计数器控制单位量
All counter control units...
把真空压力移到最大
... remove vacuum pressure to maximum.
没有作用 长官
Function negative, sir.
你不能把它击落吗?
Can't you knock them down?
完全不可能 长官 它们有新型的B20 低空回避系统
Absolutely impossible, sir. They have the new P-20 low-level avoidance systems.
给我接五角大厦
Get me the Pentagon.
如何?你认为如何?超人宝贝 有趣吗?
What do you think, super baby? Interesting?
你的理论令人印象深刻 路梭
Your theory's quite impressive, Luthor.
欧帝斯 请到美容室去 好吗?
Would you go to the viewing room, please?
但其他的部份只是幻想而己
But as for the rest, it's nothing but a sick fantasy.
幻想?
Fantasy?
不
No.
是历史 在发生中 超人
It's history. It's happening, Superman.
黛丝马克小姐
Miss Teschmacher!
什么事?赖克斯
Yes, Lex?
火箭现在在那里?
Where's the rocket now?
在大峡谷上像是扁幅一般
It's going like a bat over the Grand Canyon, so is the other one.
另一枚也是另一枚?
The other one?
有两枚?
There are two of them?
是的 超人 双重保证
Yes, Superman, double jeopardy.
即使是你与你伟大的速度 也无法阻止两枚
Even you, with your great speed, couldn't stop both of them.
但是我 另一方面来说 能用我的导向仪阻止它们
While I, on the other hand, could stop them with my detonator.
好了 路梭 它在那里?
All right, Luthor, where is it?
导向仪在哪?
Where's the detonator?
你这个神经病
Diseased maniac!
你真的以为用铅做的箱子就能够躲过我了吗?
Do you think you could hide it from me by encasing it in lead?
我把这箱子做成你的监狱铁
I'll mold this box into your prison bars.
别碰那个
Don't touch that.
我告诉过你了
I told you.
那是克莱顿陨石 超人
It's Kryptonite.
一点由你家乡来的纪念品
A little souvenir from your hometown.
我没任何花费就让你像回家一般
I've spared no expense to make you feel at home.
你在你的时代是伟大的 超人
You were great in your day.
但那有个原因
But it just stands to reason...
当你气数己尽的时候
...when it came time to cash in your chips...
那个出卖的 有病的神经病 会变成你的保管者
...this old diseased maniac would be your banker.
心智驾凌肌肉了?
Mind over muscle.
你根本不在乎另一枚飞弹击中那里 对吧?
You don't even care where the other missile's headed, do you?
我当然在乎
Certainly I do.
我晓得它要击中的准确地点
I know exactly where it's headed.
新泽西州的哈肯赛
Hackensack, New Jersey.
我现在得离开你了 不伤感情 我们都有我们的小错误
I have to leave you now. No hard feelings. We all have our little faults.
我的是加州
Mine's in California.
赖克斯 我妈往在哈肯赛
Lex, my mother lives in Hackensack.
黛丝马克小姐
Miss Teschmacher.
欧帝斯
Otis.
黛丝马克小姐
Miss Teschmacher.
Miss Teschmacher
求你 你不能…
Please, you can't...
你不能只是站在那
...you can't just stand there.
你不能只是站在那里 让无辜的人 几百万无辜的人死
You can't just stand and let millions of innocent people die.
也许
Maybe.
求你 求你帮我去救他们
Please, help me to save them.
若是我帮你 你保证先救我妈?
Would you promise to save my mother first?
露…露易丝和吉米
But, Lois, and Jimmy...
但是要先救我妈 若你答应我
But my mother comes first.
我会相信你 因为一向都说实话
If you promise, I'll believe you because you always tell the truth.
好 我答应你 我答应你
I promise, I promise.
你…为什么先吻我呢?
Why did you kiss me first?
是因为我想待会你不会吻我
I didn't think you'd let me later.
谢谢 黛丝马克小姐
Thank you, Miss Teschmacher.
我为何和好人无法相处的好呢?
Why is it I can't get it on with the good guys?
现在站到一边去吧  我也不要你留在这边
Stand aside now. I wouldn't stay here, either.
目标鸟依然朝东方飞去
Army Bird still heading due east.
小鸟依然朝西方飞去
Navy Bird still heading due west.
雷达依然有接触…
Losing radar contact.
下一次接触在3秒钟后
Next contact after three seconds.
陆军的飞弹依然朝东方飞 长官
Army Bird still headed east, sir.
陆军的飞弹逐渐脱离范围
Army Bird gaining altitude.
黛丝马克小姐
Miss Teschmacher!
雷达接触强烈 雷达接触强烈
Radar contact strong.
黛丝马克小姐
Miss Teschmacher!
雷达报告 海军飞弹在洛杉矶区
Radar report Navy Bird. San Andreas area.
海军飞弹再15秒到它的攻击区
Navy Bird heading down, 15 seconds to impact.
15秒 倒数计时中
15 seconds and counting.
一枚军用飞弹在南加州沙漠爆炸
A military missile has exploded in the Southern California desert.
这次爆炸影响到圣安得烈斯断层
The force of the explosion has activated the San Andreas fault.
使南加州产生了严重的大地震
California is suffering a major earthquake.
是怎么回事?
What's going on?
是地震
It's a quake! Look!
好了 孩子们 现在没事了
Okay, kids, it's all right now.
我的天呀
Holy mackerel!
我们要出轨了
We're going off the tracks.
所有的人员撤退本区域
All personnel evacuate dam.
当心钢索
Watch that cable
那个人去关总开关
Someone try and pull the main.
克拉克先生 它要倒塌了
It's impossible. It's red hot!
支持住 低下身去
两位 那个人没事吧?
Is that man all right?
没事
Yeah.
支持着 孩子
Hang on, Jim.
水库崩了
The dam broke.
你在这是安全的 孩子
You're safe here, son.
没关系 依连小姐随时会到
That's okay. Miss Lane will be driving by any minute.
快点 乔治 快点  我们快到山顶去
- Come on! - Make it to the hill.
南加州受到震灾严重
There has been major quake damage to Southern California.
圣安得烈斯断层奇迹式的愈合了
The San Andreas fault has miraculously sealed itself.
南加州正遭受大地震灾难的折磨
Yet Southern California is suffering an aftershock of a major earthquake.
人口依然了解要…
The population is still warned to be aware...
拜托 发动
Please, come on, turn over.
快呀
Come on!
救我 救我 不要 求你
Help me. Help me, please.
不
No.
吾儿
My son.
你禁止干预人类的历史
It is forbidden for you to interfere...
我只知道一件事 吾儿 你来这是有原因的
There's one thing I do know, Son, and that is you are here for a reason.
你禁止干预人类的历史
It is forbidden.
我能做那么多的事 所有的力量
All those things I can do. All those powers...
你禁止干预人类的历史 但我却不能救活她
... but I couldn't even save him.
是禁止的
It is forbidden.
嘿
Hi.
别麻烦了 我想是熄火了
Don't bother, it's dead.
当然是熄火了
Sure it's dead.
男人的问题是你需要他们时 一个都不见了
The problem with men of steel is they're never around when you want one.
你知道当你到处在飞的时候 我发生了什么事吗?
Do you know what happened while you were off flying around?
我几乎在地震之中 有加油站在我的车旁爆炸
I was almost in an earthquake. A gas station blew up beside my car.
有电话杆倒的满路都是 我几乎死了
Telephone poles falling all over the road. I was almost killed.
而想谈谈这整件事 而这笨车却没有了油
To top the whole thing off, this stupid car runs out of gas.
对那个我很抱歉 露易丝
I'm sorry about that, Lois.
但我忙了一阵子
But I've been kind of busy for a while.
对不起 没关系的
I'm sorry, that's all right.
多谢了 超人
Thanks a lot, Superman.
在地震时期 把我放在前不着村后不着店之处
Put me in the middle of nowhere during an earthquake.
没有食物 没有水 到处是蛇 我不晓得你是否会回头来接我
No food, no water, snakes everywhere. I had no idea if you were coming back.
嘿 超人
Hey, superman.
听我说 我还有件事必需要做  我们回头见
There's something I have to do. I'll see you later.
在一个地方待不上一秒钟
He can't stay still for a second.
老天 依连小姐 肯先生不在这看这一切真是可惜
Golly, Miss Lane, it's too bad Mr. Kent wasn't here to see all this.
是呀 可怜的克拉克 他从来不在 当超…
Yeah, poor Clark. He's never around when...
克拉克?等一等 等一等
Clark... Wait a minute.
什么事?
What?
坦白说那是个最笨的主意
Lois Lane, that is the silliest idea.
你知道吗? 让我告诉你一件事 依连小姐 我认为他真的关心你
I'll tell you something, Miss Lane. I think he really cares about you.
克拉克 他当然关心 不是克拉克
- Clark? Of course, he does. - No, not Clark.
这个 超人关心每一个人 吉米
Superman cares about everybody, Jimmy.
但 谁晓得 那一天 某幸运儿
But who knows. Someday, if he's lucky...
你弄坏了我的西装
You're messing up my suit!
欧帝斯 小心地面 你...
Otis! Watch the ground, you...
晚安 典狱长
Good evening, Warden.
我想这两个人在公平审判之前 和你在一起是够安全的
These two men should be safe here 'til they can get a fair trial.
他们是谁?超人
Who is it, Superman?
赖克斯路梭
Lex Luthor.
是我们时代中最伟大的犯罪心智
- The greatest criminal mind of our time. - Of our time.
我们的时代 这是我个人的通知
- I hereby serve notice... - He's serving notice to you.
这些围墙
...that these walls...
请你闭上嘴 好吗?
Will you shut up, you fat little fool!
好了 把他们带走 孩子们
你 你 别再打我 在牢里了
You, you nitwit!
傻瓜
Nincompoop!
这个国家
This country...
再度安全了 超人 谢谢你
...is safe again, Superman, thanks to you.
不 先生
No, sir.
别谢我 典狱长
Don't thank me, Warden.
我们全是同一队中的一部份
We're all part of the same team.
晚安
Good night.